# **Performance Test Lead**

# ROBERT SMITH

Phone: (123) 456 78 99 Email: info@qwikresume.com Website: www.gwikresume.com

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/qwikresume Address: 1737 Marshville Road,

labama.

# **Objective**

8+Years of experience in system design, Performance Engineering including Tuning, Analysis and recommendations Testing which includes Performance Automation testing in web services- SOA, web-based applications and Manual Quality Assurance. 7+ years of diverse experience as a Performance Test Engineer/Lead/Consultant with expertise in Performance Testing, Software Testing Life Cycle (STLC), Test Case Development/Automation, Test Scripting using HP LoadRunner and Jmeter.

## Skills

Performance Engineer, Development/Automation.

# **Work Experience**

#### **Performance Test Lead**

### **Broadridge Financials** - October 2014 - 2020

- Conducted work group sessions with application managers, developers.
- Business analyst for gathering requirements, analyzed requirements.
- Responsible for the creation of the test plan/strategy, test schedule, testing status reporting, test case creation, monitoring of test case execution and script execution where needed.
- Involved in test environment build and designed Load (capacity) model on the basis of current volume and projected percentage increase in volume.
- Integrated Performance Testing with various applications as well as within a Cloud environment.
- Build HP-StormRunner Load Tests(Scenarios) for cloud performance testing-2015 Extensively Worked in Web, Citrix, Click and Script, Oracle Protocol, Seibel, Winsock, Soap protocols, Web Services, RTE, SAPGUI.
- Reviewed scripts that were developed by teammates and verified scripts in the standalone mode.

#### **Performance Test Lead**

#### **Delta Corporation** - 2012 - 2014

- Developed Master Test Plan, which includes entire Testing Plan, Testing Resources, Testing Strategy and testing of end-to-end performance scenarios.
- Project Duration October 2012 to till date Team Size 2 Performance testers Tools VSTS 2013
  Project Overview The Retail Asset Distribution (RAD) .
- RAD is user friendly frontend application to search, find, share, download, Upload and export sales and marketing assets to generate new marketing.
- The application has Three user interfaces Admins, Consumers and Authors.
- Environment Windows Server, SQL Server 2008 R2, BizTalk , IIS, Azure and Share point Project 5.
- Project Duration February 2014 to September 2015 Team Size 6 performance testers Tool VSTS 2013 Project Overview This project primarily helps.
- This is mainly capability testing, which covers testing of IIS, SQL and BizTalk.

Education	
Bachelor's in IT - 2003(JNTU - Hyderabad, Andhra Pradesh)	